Elyza Bleau

310-890-2381 | elyzableau.om@gmail.com | Astoria, NY https://www.linkedin.com/in/elyzableau | https://github.com/bleauwonder https://elyzableau.herokuapp.com/

Career Summary

Full Stack Web Developer specializing in front-end framework with the desire to create functional code and beautifully designed websites that positively impact the end-user. Brings over ten years of administrative leadership, collaboration with teaching experience and writing expertise from a wide range of industries. An innovative and creative spirit with a love of coding detective work.

Technical Skills

JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, Sass, jQuery, Bootstrap, Materialize, MySQL, Handlebars, React.js, Node.js, Heroku, GitHub Flow, Terminal Command, Basic Computer Science, Responsive Design, WordPress, Agile and SCRUM methodology, Microsoft Exchange, O365, Mac, PC, Google Suite, Cloud-Based Solutions, Canvas, ADP, Adobe DC: advanced Photoshop/Lightroom

Professional Skills

Project Coordination, Office Management, Vendor Management, Customer Service, Public Speaking/Presentations, Training, Teaching, Lesson Plans, Scheduling, Problem Solving, Recruiting, Employee Relations, Writing Articles/Blogs

Education

Columbia University New York, NY | Full Stack Web Development Certificate (2019)
University of California San Diego La Jolla, CA | Master of Education Elementary and Music Mount St. Joseph University Cincinnati, OH | Bachelor of Arts Music (French Horn)

Applications Built

Cartoon Friend Finder | Full-Stack Application

An application to help you find your best match in a cartoon friend

- Class homework enhanced by adding more design and theme elements. A survey that matches the user with a personally created API of cartoon characters. The user is also, then, added to the API without persistence
- Used HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, node.js, AJAX
- https://salty-sea-60327.herokuapp.com/

I Love Sitcoms | Front-End Application with 2 APIs

A just-for-fun application to gather information and gifs on sitcoms and add your own

- Class homework enhanced by the idea of adding a second API that adds information on each sitcom in a dynamic environment
- Used HTML, Bootstrap, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery, Giphy API, OMDB API
- https://bleauwonder.github.io/Giphy-Time/

Sun Records Trivia | Front-End Application

Timed trivia game application about Sun Records

- Class homework enhanced by making each question its own dynamic slide and a 60 second timer for all 10
 questions
- Used HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery
- https://bleauwonder.github.io/TriviaGame/

Professional Experience

YAI Network | Junior Human Resources Generalist | New York, NY

09/2018 - Present

Recruited and provided Employee Relations for 5 clinics and all residential nursing, specifically bringing in LPNs, RNs, MDs, OTs, PTs, and LMSWs.

- Successfully created requisitions by writing accurate and correct job descriptions and posting them in ADP and job boards while screening candidates for initial contact with hiring manager
- Effectively researched and implemented best office practices to help streamline processes with SharePoint and spreadsheets to solve hiring issues
- Supported employees to work through problems with each other in a proactive way
- Ad hoc help with central office recruiting (finding a Web Development star, a CRM guru, and a database manager

YAI Network | Project Coordinator | New York, NY

02/2018-09/2018

Used knowledge of information technologies improvement methodologies, including, but not limited to large Non-Profit agencies, Telecomm, Healthcare, Cloud Services (Azure), and Apple support while leading IT team in Agile huddles.

- Effectively created spreadsheets, presentations and other deliverables using Microsoft Office 365 as necessary for client engagement. Identified potential engagement sources and potential add-on opportunities
- Successfully developed content and taught Office 365 in a training environment with a small team, in preparation for an organization-wide migration
- Coordinated best development practices to reach the company-wide fundraising goal, as well as participated as a key team member in filming and introducing Virtual Reality videos to the greater YAI community

Freelance | Photographer | New York, NY

02/2015-Present

Take photographs for events and headshots

- Utilize Photoshop and Lightroom to adjust photos to look inviting on the web and in print
- Help clients build their brand through the stories they tell in their photographs

Freelance | WordPress Developer/Branding Specialist | Los Angeles, CA/NY, NY

05/2007-03/2016

Created websites on Wordpress.org and taught other entrepreneurs how to use it over Wix and Square Space

- Utilized HTML to adjust templates to make them as custom as possible
- Helped other entrepreneurs find their voice in their brand, website, and photos

TKO Suites | Office and Account Manager (Contract) | New York, NY

10/2016-12/2016

- Helped to sell potential small business owners on leasing open offices
- Handled all client relations including up-to-date payments
- Arranged for office cleaning and furniture rearrangement for offices

Bustle | Office Manager (Contract) | New York, NY

09/2015-01/2016

- Managed all inventory for the office, including the snacks and office supplies
- Copy edited and added product links to old and new Bustle articles.
- Aided in the planning and ordering for big office events.

Park East Animal Hospital | Client Services / Social Media/Blog Editor (Contract) | NY, NY

08/2015-09/2015

- Wrote new doctor biographies; researched and wrote content for the hospital blog and Facebook page
- Answered multiple phone lines and directed calls to the correct doctor
- Utilized Cornerstone to enter information and create reports for senior management

Zeno Consulting Inc | Executive Assistant | Culver City, CA

09/2011-03/2014

- Maintained guarterly financial reports for all clients
- Organized and streamlined all office procedures to run efficiently for two Vice Presidents
- Edited and proofread all in house literature such as newsletters and outgoing client content

Sylvan Learning Center | Instructor | Studio City, CA

09/2005-12/2007

- Instructed three students of various ages on many subjects, including math, reading, writing, as well as how to develop effective study skills.
- Aided students in the completion of homework.
- Helped develop a more restructured way to teach three students at a time to give each student special attention.

Do Rite Records | Office Manager / Executive Assistant to CEO | Agoura Hills, CA

09/2006-11/2007

- Simplified office procedures and created an efficient work environment through processes such as filing, rearranging and developing new reports.
- Booked domestic travel for CEO.
- Utilized QuickBooks to manage all expenses.

Volunteer Activities/Additional Skills

- Professional musician, and public speaker/storyteller
- Full-Stack Web Development for entrepreneurial friends
- Facilitator in starting the nonprofit Root Culture, educating about permaculture and healthy eating
- Staff at an urban farm in Queens farming, teaching, and selling at markets
- · Active member of Hudson River Community Sailing,
- Teacher volunteer at the Santa Monica Pier Aquarium
- 500-hour certified yoga instructor, music instructor, tutor, health coach